<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Blog on tripleo1's blog</title><link>https://tripleo1.github.io/blog/</link><description>Recent content in Blog on tripleo1's blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2023 14:50:00 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://tripleo1.github.io/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Faces vs Vases</title><link>https://tripleo1.github.io/blog/faces-vs-vases/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2023 14:50:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://tripleo1.github.io/blog/faces-vs-vases/</guid><description>When there is light on our planet, it comes from the sky, not from earth. Our vision knows this perfectly even though it was not until a few years ago that the psychologist Vilyanur Ramachandran, from the University of California, San Diego, came up with these splendid examples. The actual effect of the direction of the light determining whether we see shapes as concave or convex was described by David Brewster in the 1800s.</description></item><item><title>KDE vs GNOME development meme</title><link>https://tripleo1.github.io/blog/kde-vs-gnome-development-meme/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Mar 2023 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tripleo1.github.io/blog/kde-vs-gnome-development-meme/</guid><description>Original URL: https://www.bassi.io/~ebassi/GNOMEvKDE.md
This is NOT my response to the oh-so-dull and typical flame-wars regarding whether the GNOME or KDE desktop is &amp;ldquo;best&amp;rdquo;. I have an opinion on that, but that&amp;rsquo;s not what this is about. This is about how I picture the development process of each of those fine desktop products.
Warning to readers: this is mildly offensive, however it&amp;rsquo;s not particularly obscene, for most values of obscene. On a flame-o-riffic scale of one to ten, it rates about a seventy-three.</description></item><item><title>Introduction to E-LOG</title><link>https://tripleo1.github.io/blog/introduction-to-e-log/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Dec 2021 19:53:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://tripleo1.github.io/blog/introduction-to-e-log/</guid><description>I printed out my examples to see what was really happening with them. I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing this thing for a while now called problem sets or problem statements, that detail the difference between the expected output and the output that is generated (by GenerateC, and by extension, by DeduceTypes2). The object of that exercise is that there is somewhere between the source code of the examples (and the accompanying standard library (alot of stubs in its current incarnation)), and the output, which is not generating the right results, and that is THE PROCESS.</description></item><item><title>Introduction to SLIR</title><link>https://tripleo1.github.io/blog/introduction-to-slir/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Nov 2021 20:54:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://tripleo1.github.io/blog/introduction-to-slir/</guid><description>There is a branch in git I have called pull-model. What it&amp;rsquo;s designed to do is assert the liveness of certain parts of a [set of] source code. These certain parts are classes/namespaces, functions and member variables. [What about deciding the types of specifically member variables?] It&amp;rsquo;s not meant to work on the inside of a function (code paths and things like that). Specifically, it was created to create ClassInvocations and FunctionInvocations.</description></item><item><title>Les Misérables by Victor Hugo</title><link>https://tripleo1.github.io/blog/les-mis%C3%A9rables-by-victor-hugo/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Dec 2015 04:05:25 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://tripleo1.github.io/blog/les-mis%C3%A9rables-by-victor-hugo/</guid><description>Although this detail has no connection whatever with the real substance of what we are about to relate, it will not be superfluous, if merely for the sake of exactness in all points, to mention here the various rumors and remarks which had been in circulation about him from the very moment when he arrived in the diocese.
Bool True or false, that which is said of men often occupies as important a place in their lives, and above all in their destinies, as that which they do.</description></item><item><title>Metamorphosis by Franz Kafka</title><link>https://tripleo1.github.io/blog/metamorphosis-by-franz-kafka/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Dec 2015 04:03:46 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://tripleo1.github.io/blog/metamorphosis-by-franz-kafka/</guid><description>Part One One morning, when Gregor Samsa woke from troubled dreams, he found himself transformed in his bed into a horrible vermin.
He lay on his armour-like back, and if he lifted his head a little he could see his brown belly, slightly domed and divided by arches into stiff sections.
The bedding was hardly able to cover it and seemed ready to slide off any moment. His many legs, pitifully thin compared with the size of the rest of him, waved about helplessly as he looked.</description></item><item><title>Use @ instead of HEAD</title><link>https://tripleo1.github.io/blog/use-at-instead-of-head/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Aug 2015 17:09:14 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://tripleo1.github.io/blog/use-at-instead-of-head/</guid><description>I recently discovered that from git version 1.8.5 onwards, @ can replace HEAD:
$ git reset --hard @~2 $ git rebase -i @~10 $ git diff @~2..@~3 And also in most scenarios HEAD can be left out completely, so you can say:
$ git reset -- @{2} instead of:
$ git reset -- HEAD@{2} It takes some getting used to, but it&amp;rsquo;s definitely faster than typing HEAD.</description></item></channel></rss>